A murder in the past. A mystery in the future.
Last Night in Soho is a horror, mystery film directed by Edgar Wright.
A young girl, passionate about fashion design, is mysteriously able to enter the
1960s where she encounters her idol, a dazzling wannabe singer.
But 1960s London is not what it seems, and time seems to
be falling apart with shady consequences.
Eloise Turner, played by Thomasin McKenzie.
Sandie, played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
Jack, played by Matt Smith.
Peggy Turner, played by Rita Tushingham.
John, played by Michael Ajao.
Jocasta, played by Synnøve Karlsen.
Last Night in Soho is a 2021 British psychological horror film directed and
co-produced by Edgar Wright, and co-written by Wright and Krysty Wilson-Cairns.
It stars Thomasin McKenzie as a naive teenager who moves to London to study fashion design; there she is haunted by visions
of Sandie (played by Anya Taylor-Joy), a glamorous young woman who had lived during the Swinging Sixties.
The cast also features Matt Smith, Terence Stamp, Rita Tushingham, and Michael
Ajao, with Diana Rigg and Margaret Nolan in their final film roles.
Rigg and Nolan died in 2020, and the film is dedicated to their memories.
Following its premiere at the 78th Venice International Film Festival on 4 September 2021, Last Night in Soho was released
theatrically in the UK and the US on 29 October 2021 by Universal Pictures and Focus Features, respectively.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its technical aspects, direction
and performances, while its writing received some criticism (especially the ending).
The film grossed $23 million worldwide on a budget of $43 million.
The film was nominated for two BAFTA Film Awards, including
Outstanding British Film and Best Sound.
The film explores themes of london, england, nightmare,
go-go dancer, time travel, nostalgia.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.